Chapter 18. His mark.
As we were walking down the end of the warf towards the ship, Quiquake carrying
his harpoon, Captain Pelleg in his gruff voice loudly hailed us from his wigwam,
saying he had not suspected my friend was a cannibal, and furthermore
announcing that he let no cannibals on board that craft unless they previously
produced their papers. "What do you mean by that, Captain Pelleg?" said I, now
jumping on the bull works and leaving my comrade standing on the warf. I mean, he
replied, he must show his papers. Yes, said Captain Bildad in his hollow voice,
sticking his head from behind Pellegs out of the wigwam. He must show that
he's converted. Son of darkness, he added, turning towag. Art thou at
present in communion with any Christian church?
Why, said I. He is a member of the first congregational church. Here be it said
that many tattooed savages sailing in Nantucket ships at last come to be converted into churches
first congregational church cried Bildad what that worships in Deacon Deuteronomy
Coleman's meeting house and so saying taking out his spectacles he rubbed them
with his great yellow bandana handkerchief and putting them on very
carefully came out of the wigwam and leaning stiffly over the bull works took
a good long look at Queig.
How long has he been a member? He then said, turning to me. Not very long, I
rather guess, young man.
No, said Pelleg. And he hasn't been baptized right either, or it would have
washed some of that devil's blue off his face.
Do tell now, cried Bildad. Is this Philistine a regular member of Deacon
Deuteronomy's meeting? I never saw him going there, and I pass it every Lord's day.
I don't know anything about Deacon Deuteronomy or his meeting, said I. All
I know is that Quiqu here is a born member of the First Congregational
Church. He is a deacon himself. Quiques.
Young man, said Bildad sternly, thou art skylarking with me. Explain thyself,
thou young Hittite. What church does thee mean? Answer me.
Finding myself thus hardpushed, I replied, "I mean, sir, the same ancient
Catholic church to which you and I, and Captain Pelleg there, and Quiqu here,
and all of us, and every mother, son, and soul of us belong, the great and
everlasting first congregation of this whole worshiing world. We all belong to
that. Only some of us cherish some queer crotchets, in no way touching the grand
belief. In that we all join hands.
Splice thou means splice hands? cried Pelleg drawing nearer. Young man, you'd
better ship for a missionary instead of a form hand. I never heard a better
sermon. Deacon Deuteronomy. Why, Father Mappel himself couldn't beat it. And
he's reckoned something. Come aboard.
Come aboard. Never mind about the papers. I say tell Quhog there. What's
that you call him? Tell Quohog to step along by the great anchor. What a
harpoon he's got there. Looks like good stuff that and he handles it about
right. I say Quhog or whatever your name is. Did you ever stand in the head of a
whaleboat? Did you ever strike a fish?
without saying a word, Quiqu in his wild sort of way, jumped upon the bull works,
from thence into the boughs of one of the whaleboats hanging to the side, and
then bracing his left knee and poisoning his harpoon, cried out in some such way
as this, "Captain, you see him small drop tar on water there. You see him?"
Well, suppose him one whale eye. Well then, and taking sharp aim at it, he
darted the iron right over Bildad's broadbrim clean across the ship's deck,
and struck the glistening tar spot out of sight. Now, saidwiquely
hauling in the line. Sposey him.
Why that whale dead?
Quick, build, said Pelleg, his partner, who a gasast at the close vicinity of
the flying harpoon, had retreated towards the cabin gangwing. Quick, I say
you, Bildad, and get the ship's papers.
We must have hedgehog, I mean Quog, in one of our boats. Look, you Quhog, we'll
give you the 90th lay, and that's more than ever was given a harpooner yet out of Nantucket.
So down we went into the cabin, and to my great joy, Quiquake was soon enrolled
among the same ship's company to which I myself belong. When all preliminaries
were over, and Pelleg had got everything ready for signing, he turned to me and
said, "I guess Quog there don't know how to write, does he?" I say, "Quhog, blast
ye. Dust thou sign thy name or make thy mark?" But at this question, Queue, who
had twice or thrice before taken part in similar ceremonies, looked no ways
abashed, but taking the offered pen, copied upon the paper in the proper
place, an exact counterpart of the queer round figure which was tattooed upon his
arm, so that through Captain Pelleg's obstinate mistake touching his appellet,
it stood something like this. Quohog, his mark X.
Meanwhile, Captain Bildad sat earnestly and steadfastly eyeing Qui Quag, and at
last, rising solemnly and fumbling in the huge pockets of his broad skirted
drab coat, took out a bundle of tracks, and selecting one entitled The Latterday
Coming, or No Time to Lose, placed it in Quiqu's hands, and grasping them and the
book with both his, looked earnestly into his eyes, and said, "Son of
darkness, I must do my duty by thee. I am part owner of this ship, and feel
concerned for the souls of all its crew.
If thou still clingst to thy pagan ways, which I sadly fear, I beseech thee,
remain not, for I, a beial bondsman, spurn the idle bell, and the hideous
dragon. Turn from the wrath to come.
Mind thine eye, I say. Oh, goodness gracious. Steer clear of the fiery pit.
Something of the salt sea yet lingered in old Billad's language heterogeneously
mixed with scriptural and domestic phrases.
A vast there, a vast there, Bildad. A vast now spoiling our harpooner, cried
Pelleg. Pious harpineers never make good voyagers. It takes the shark out of
them. No harpineer is worth a straw who ain't pretty sharkish. There was young
Nat Swain, once the bravest boat header out of all Nantucket in the vineyard. He
joined the meeting and never came to good. He got so frightened about his
plagy soul that he shrked and steered away from Wales for fear of afterlapse
in case he got stove and went to Davy Jones.
Pelleg, Pelleg, said Bildad, lifting his eyes and hands. Thou thyself, as I
myself, hast seen many a perilous time.
Thou knowest, Pelleg, what it is to have the fear of death. How then canst thou
pray in this ungodly guise? Thou belst thine own heart, Pelleg. Tell me, when
this same Peekquad here had her three mass overboard in that typhoon on Japan,
that same voyage when thou went mate with Captain Ahab, did thou not think of
death and the judgment? Then "Hear him! Hear him now!" Oh, cried
Pelleg, marching across the cabin and thrusting his hands far down into his
pockets. Hear him all of you. Think of that. When every moment we thought the
ship would sink, death and the judgment then what? With all three mass making
such an everlasting thundering against the side, and every sea breaking over us
for and a half. Think of death and the judgment then. No, no time to think
about death. Then life was what Captain Ahab and I was thinking of. And how to
save all hands, how to rig jury mass, how to get into the nearest port. That's
what I was thinking of.
Bildad said no more, buttoning up his coat, stalked on deck, where we followed
him. There he stood, very quietly, overlooking some sail makers who were
mending a top sail in the waist. Now and then he stooped to pick up a patch or
save an end of tarred twine which otherwise might have been wasted.